<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Blown to Bits | Mark's Code Corner]]></title>
  <link href="http://codecornerapps.github.io/blog/categories/blown-to-bits/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://codecornerapps.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2015-02-12T17:05:08-05:00</updated>
  <id>http://codecornerapps.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Mark Robinson]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Importance of Owning a Website]]></title>
    <link href="http://codecornerapps.github.io/blog/2015/02/12/the-importance-of-owning-a-website/"/>
    <updated>2015-02-12T16:30:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://codecornerapps.github.io/blog/2015/02/12/the-importance-of-owning-a-website</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Today, one of my friends asked me if he should buy a .com website. At the time, I didn&rsquo;t know why he&rsquo;d even need to own one &ndash; so I asked &ldquo;why do you want to own a website?&rdquo; He told me that he wants to own a place on the internet that&rsquo;ll let him develop more complex applications that use MySQL to store user and project data. He also said that he wanted to make a blog. Given these circumstances, I thought it&rsquo;d be a awesome endeavor for him. I recommended a website host with accordingly priced plans that would suit his needs.</p>

<p>Not everyone needs to buy a website domain to have a public space on the Internet. Many script kiddies and bloggers are satisfied registering a subdomain of a domain like Google Sites. Their visitors would navigate to &lsquo;sites.google.com/site/my-site&rsquo; where &lsquo;my-site&rsquo; is the name of a site. Many visitors dislike navigating to this structure because of its long web address. Some visitors may distrust the site owner for publishing a site on another organization&rsquo;s domain. Also, visitors would rather type a small and relevant web address than type a long, mostly redundant, web address.</p>

<p>However, you will need a domain name in the future when you want to have more website functionality than Google Sites provides. It&rsquo;ll be handy to have in a résumé. Background server side processes like cron jobs, automatic backup, maintainance of unlimited traffic / storage / subdomains / email addresses / etc, and MySQL database will only be available to you if you rent or own a server. That&rsquo;s why you need a domain, and what you can do with it. The possibilities are only limited by your imagination at that point.</p>

<p>If you don&rsquo;t have your own domain name, buy one. They&rsquo;re cheap and you won&rsquo;t regret your purchase. Best of all, if you ever decide that you don&rsquo;t need a domain name, simply let the registration expire.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[What the Older Generation Wants in Portable PCs]]></title>
    <link href="http://codecornerapps.github.io/blog/2015/02/10/what-the-older-generation-wants-in-portable-pcs/"/>
    <updated>2015-02-10T23:40:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://codecornerapps.github.io/blog/2015/02/10/what-the-older-generation-wants-in-portable-pcs</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I was recently asked to recommend a computer for the older generation. So I thought to myself, “what would this older generation want to have in its computers?” &ndash; so I asked my mother. She noticed many features that she would desire for her computer to have. For instance, she is jealous that I can talk into my phone&rsquo;s microphone to ask Google, “What&rsquo;s the weather?” She would like to hear her laptop answer her questions. She&rsquo;s getting older hence, she wants the answers instantaneously. She&rsquo;s frustrated by typing. She wants a more user-friendly computer that she can bond with. She wants a virtual personal assistant that would connect to banking finances to pay bills without hassle. Unfortunately, the technology isn&rsquo;t to that level of interconnectivity with voice yet.</p>

<p>Portable computers called “chromebooks” offer Google voice search. Each chromebook has a microphone built-in. So, I recommended the current Amazon best selling chromebook, the Acer C720, to my mother. It&rsquo;s easily portable, has long battery life and best of all, has active voice search functionality. With this chromebook, she would have the capability to ask questions to Google and receive responses that mirror the responses of my Nexus 5&rsquo;s Google voice searches; It would be an interactive and personable experience. My mother already uses Google Drive&rsquo;s suite of office tools with her Google account so, it was a great choice. She&rsquo;s already familiar with the fundamentals of a cloud-based system. The tighter integration between these tools and chromebooks would be icing on the cake.</p>

<p>The older generation seems to want personal computers with built-in features that “just work out of the box.” In addition, my mother dreads configuring settings because she doesn&rsquo;t know nor want to learn about the inner workings of programs that run in the background. The chromebook is the answer to this predicament. They are minimal effort machines that work right out of the box. There is no device available on the market to date with built-in features that would serve my aging mother better than a chromebook would.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
